💌 bahar.hosseini@gmail.com 🔇 bahosseini.com 📞 548 333 3707 👂 Waterloo, ON 🛮 in bahar-hosseini 🖸 bahar-hosseini

### SUMMARY

I am a passionate full-stack developer who loves solving real-world problems using software. I have experience working in different teams in high-tech IT companies, which helps me to look at problems from different angles. I enjoy writing clean and readable code, and creating websites that are easy to navigate. My goal is not only to grow as an individual, but also to help my team grow and succeed.

# **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript, NodeJS, Ruby, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES: React, Redux, ExpressJS, Rails, Next.js, jQuery, Saas (SCSS), Tailwind CSS, EJS

DATABASES: PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB TESTING: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Storybook, Cypress

OTHERS: LINUX, Git, Github, Heroku, AWS technologies (EC2, S3, Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB), Agile Methodology

#### **PROJECTS**

Campr Oct. 2022

Campr is an app inspired by AirBnB that allows people without access to camping gears to rent gears from locals with ones to spare.

Tech stack: React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

jungle-rails Sept. 2022

A mini e-commerce application built with Rails 6.1 . This app allows users to add a variety of plants to their carts and order them.

Tech stack: Rails, PostgreSQL, cypress

Appointment Scheduler Sept. 2022

A React based app enabling students to book new/ edit previously booked appointments with their chosen mentor in real-time.

Tech stack: React

Test: storybook, cypress, Jest

#### Buy/Sell Listing Website Aug. 2022

An online store app where admins can post different types of products to sell, remove items, or mark them as SOLD! Users are able to favorite items to check up on them later, filter items by price, and also send messages to admin to negotiate the price. Admins can reply to the user by the app and email.

Tech stack: Express, Node, jQuery, PostgreSQL

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### **Pishro Cloud Computing**

Project Manager · Mar. 2018 to July 2019

- Managing project plans using Jira, MSP, and agile practices to ensure each team meets their objectives and product delivery timelines.
- Delivering product tests with the technical team to detect software bugs.
- Effectively collaborating with DevOps, Front-End, and Back-End teams.
- Contributing functional and technical support to end-users in testing environments including investigating system errors and using Horizon (Open Stack) to launch virtual machine instances.

#### **Sharif ICT Innovation Center**

Project Management Assistant · Aug. 2017 to Mar. 2018

- Providing vital daily and periodic project progress and status reports to top management and stakeholders.
- Performing quality assurance and testing to ensure the quality of the system is maintained.
- Managing tickets and logging daily IT issues to successfully addressing the users' issues on time.

# Senobar Printing House

Project Coordinator · Oct. 2014 to July 2015

- Creating WBS and managing time, scope, and cost constraints.
- Preparing project documents and generating reports for stakeholders.

# **EDUCATION**

Lighthouse Labs Oct. 2022

Diploma Lighthouse Labs Full-Stack Web Developer

Iran Azad University, Science and Research Branch 2022

Candidate for M.Sc. Industrial Engineering

Iran University of Science and Technology Sept. 2015

B.Sc. Industrial Engineering